【家长提示】本片的评级为 TV-14-V，可能包含暴力等内容，
因而不建议 14 岁以下儿童独自观赏。
50年过去了
50 years have passed,
我的年岁却没有跟着增长
but I do not age.
时间  再无撼动我一丝一毫
Time has lost its effect on me.
折磨  却从未停止
Yet the suffering continues.
阿蛊的魔爪扼住了过去
Aku's grasp chokes the past,
现在  乃至未来
present, and future.
希望已然消逝
Hope is lost.
必须回去
Gotta get back,
回到过去
back to the past.
杰克武士
Samurai Jack.
Translated by @SerCom_KC
OPEN TRANSLATION PROJECT
翻译版本  v1.0.0-CHS
翻译  妙挖種子
校对  SerCom_KC
噢  你好啊  小家伙
Oh! Hello, little friend.
这山顶上是不是有一个时空隧道？
I don't suppose you know if there is a time portal atop this mountain, do you?
你也不清楚？
No?
还是？
Yes?
阿蛊一直都在破坏时空隧道
Aku has destroyed many.
现在剩下来的大概没多少了吧
I worry that there are none left.
Phew!
差一点点啊
That was close!
没想到你这么快就跑到这儿来了
I didn't think you'd get here so fast.
真是愚蠢！
Fool!
对了  讲个笑话
Oh, fun fact --
那可是最后一个时空隧道哦
that was the last remaining time portal in existence!
哇  好气啊！
Ooh, so angry!
注意身体啊  武士
Be careful, Samurai --
这样下去是会气出心脏病的喔
so much stress will give you a heart attack.
哎呀  我干嘛要说这个呢
Ooh! What am I saying?
您就气您的吧
Please continue!
刚才就当我什么都没说
Never mind what I said!
Whoa!
Ho, ho!
想得美  武士
Not so fast, Samurai.
我可不会乖乖挨那把剑砍
I know better than to mess with that sword!
我就先走一步了
But before I go,
送你那群小家伙当出气筒吧
I'll leave you someone to play with.
自从那天起
And so...
我就再也找不到它了
I was not able to find it again.
就是那里
There!
我们到了
We are here.
不在这里
It's not here.
会不会有谁把它拿走了？
Could someone else have taken it?
不可能的
No.
我现在终于想通了
I realize now that...
不是我弄丢了剑
I did not lose the sword...
而是剑离开了我
but the sword left me.
谢谢你  朋友
Thank you, friend.
嗯  谢谢你
Yes, thank you.
我不知道这一去要什么时候才能回来
I do not know how long this may take.
我跟你去不就好了
I'll go with you.
绝对不行
You cannot.
这是我一个人的旅程
It is something that I must do on my own.
等等  我…
Wait, I...
噢  那我就…
Oh. I guess I'll just...
等你吧
wait here.
你是否心存迷惘？
Are you lost?
是
Yes.
很好
Good.
进来沏杯茶吧
Come make tea.
给我站住！
Hold it.
你们想干什么？
Where do you think you're going?
上到山顶  杀了武士
Up the mountain, to kill the Samurai.
跟你有什么关系吗？
What's it to you?
有我在  你们休想再前进一步
I'm going to stop you.
喂  怎么不走了  啥事儿那么好笑？
Hey, why have we stopped? What's so funny?
有个小丫头挡在前面
It's a girl!
说什么休想再进一步之类的
She says she's going to stop us.
他说啥？
What did he say?
大概是松鼠什么的吧
Something about a squirrel.
松鼠啊  太棒了
I love squirrels!
要准备吃午餐了吗？
Is it lunch already?
你个小不点  还能阻止我们整个军队？
So a little thing like you is gonna stop this whole army, huh?
能啊
Yep.
我们可是要把你千刀万剐
We're gonna rip you apart in a bunch of pieces,
然后堆起来  再把你碎尸万段的喔
and then we're gonna take those pieces and rip them apart into even more pieces!
放马过来啊
I'm waiting.
Hmm?!
Huh?
母亲？
Mother?
我就知道你会让我们蒙羞
I knew you would fail us.
你是最厉害的  却也是最不能专注的
You were the strongest, but the most unfocused.
很容易分心  对什么东西都抱有疑问
Always distracted, questioning everything.
不过现在回头还不晚
But all that can change.
你仍然可以为吾主带去无上的荣耀
You can still honor our Lord Father.
消灭武士  阿喜
Destroy the Samurai, Ashi.
不
No.
你对一切的看法都是错误的
You were wrong about everything.
而杰克让我看清了真相
Jack showed me the truth.
那么  你也是死路一条了
Then you, too, will die.
你为什么要站在你亲人的对立面？
How could you betray your family?
他杀了你的姐妹！
He killed your sisters!
你却放他生路
And you let him live!
不对  杀了她们的人是你！
No, you killed them!
对你来说  我们诞生的意义只有一个
We were made for one purpose --
那就是杀戮！
to kill!
我们的命运从出生起就被你封死了
Our fate was sealed the day we were born!
那武士是我们的宿敌
The Samurai is our mortal enemy.
就算不惜代价  也得让他死
He must die at any cost.
不
No.
这还真是糟糕啊
This is terrible.
真的？
Really?
正是
Yes.
此可谓  糟糕至极
Yes, quite terrible.
虽然这杯茶蕴含了所有必要的材料
This tea has all the necessary ingredients...
但是偏偏少了最重要的一味
but it lacks the most important one --
平衡
balance.
我知道你为什么会在寻找剑的途中陷入迷惘了
I see why your path to the sword remains clouded.
难道不是这条路吗？
This isn't the path?!
我不明白
I don't understand.
还望您务必指点一二
Then you must show me the way!
我做不到
I cannot.
能为你指明道路的人不是我
It is not for me to show you your path.
这家伙就知道搪塞人
That's fortune cookie nonsense!
他知道剑在哪儿  他就是故意不告诉你
He knows where it is. He just won't tell you.
拜托  请一定要告诉我
Please, you must tell me.
此物只可由你自己争取
That is something you must earn.
争取？！
Earn?!
我们所经历的这一切
After everything we've done,
所忍受的这一切
everything we've been through --
死亡  痛失  以及折磨  如此种种
the death, the loss, the suffering!
你有什么资格不把我们应有的东西还回来？！
Who are you to deny us what is rightfully ours?!
够了
Enough.
我们丢了剑的原因就在于你
We have lost the sword because of you.
没有我  我们哪里能活到今天！
I have kept us alive!
他才是把剑从我们身边夺走的家伙！
He's the one who has taken it from us!
他知道剑在哪里！
He knows where it is!
不
No.
你对我的侵蚀实在是太久了
I've let you consume me for far too long.
你休想阻挠我
You're in my way.
你
You.
你把所有的过去都掩盖了起来
You are the one who has kept the past hidden.
以你的愤怒  你的挫折
Your anger, your frustration.
你就是个傻子！
You're a fool!
你让我们蒙蔽了双眼
You have blinded us,
但我已经看开了
but now I can see.
你需要我！
You need me!
这样你就平衡了
Now you are balanced.
汝与父一同  乃天选之人
Like your father, you have been chosen.
身负遏阻极邪之使命
To stop a force of ultimate evil.
汝有这个资格
You are worthy.
阿喜
Ashi.
杰克？
Jack?
是我
Yes.
在下正是
It is me.
你拿回你的剑了
You got your sword.
还刮了胡子剃了头？
And a shave and a haircut.
嗯  确实
Hmm, yes.
而你…
And you...
看来你也没闲着呢
you have been very busy.
Ow.
谢谢你
Thank you.
那么  接下来呢？
So, what next?
阿蛊！
Aku!
♪ Watch out ♪
♪ Gotta get back ♪
♪ Back to the past ♪
♪ Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack ♪
♪ Samurai Jack ♪
♪ Wa-Watch out ♪
第玖拾捌集
♪ Gotta get back, back to the past, Samurai Jack ♪
♪ Watch out ♪
♪ Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack ♪
♪ Gotta get back ♪
♪ Samurai Jack ♪
♪ Wa-Watch out ♪